[MUSIC]
[음악]
We've built a model.
모델을 세웠지요
We understood it's accuracy about 0.911%.
정확도가 0.911인 것도 압니다
Let's go and actually use this model for something, something actually quite cool.
이 모델을 통해 멋진 걸 하나 해봅시다
So what I'm gonna do is Apply the model.
모델 적용하기
Learned model to understand sentiment for
학습한 모델을 통해 기린에 대한
our friend, the Giraffe.
감성 이해하기
So, here we go.
만들어볼까요
Let's understand it a little bit.
생각해봅시다
So here's what I'm gonna do.
이렇게 할 겁니다
I'm going to take those giraffe_reviews that I built a little bit earlier.
좀 전에 만든 giraffe_reviews에
And, I'm gonna create a new column to this
predicted_sentiment라는
giraffe_reviews called my predicted_sentiment.
새 열을 생성합니다
And this predicted_sentiment is gonna come from
predicted_sentiment는
taking the sentiment model that we build.
감성 모델을 통해 생성합니다
The sentiment model, and oops,
감성 모델
this auto-complete was a little slow, sorry about that.
자동완성이 좀 느리네요 죄송합니다
Oh man, we have a little glitch there.
문제가 좀 있군요
So Okay, we'll take the sentiment model and
감성 모델에서 예측 함수를
we're going to call this function predict on it.
호출합니다
And we'll try to predict how does it feel about the giraffe_reviews.
giraffe_reviews에 대한 느낌을 예측합니다
So how do you feel about my friend: the giraffe_reviews.
giraffe_reviews에 대해 어떤 느낌이 드시나요
And the output, and this is a key thing,
출력은, 이게 중요한데
we're not just gonna output the zero-one,
감성처럼 0-1이
where they predict the sentiment to be zero or one.
출력되는게 아니라
I'm gonna say output probability And if you remember,
확률이 나오고
we just talked about this in the module, that by outputting probability,
이 모듈에서 설명해 드렸는데 확률을 출력함으로써
you can get a more fine grain estimate what the prediction looks like.
예측에 대한 세밀한 추정이 가능해 집니다
So, we just run it and
돌려서
just let's take a quick look at what this new giraffe_reviews look like.
giraffe_reviews가 어떻게 생겼는지 보죠
So let's look at the head of this table, and you'll see that now we have
이 표의 헤드를 봅니다 그러면
the name of the product, the review, the rating, the word count.
상품명, 리뷰, 평점, 단어수가 있습니다
And I added another column called the predicted sentiment.
예측 감성을 열로 추가했지요
And for some reviews it's really high 0.999, 0.99,
몇몇 리뷰는 아주 높은 0.999, 0.99을 가지고
and here's a review that's pretty low sentiment.
여기 이 리뷰는 아주 낮은 감성을 보입니다
There should really be a large warning on the,
안 좋아하는지 이유가 여기 어디 있을 텐데
they don't like it for some reason, now let's try to understand.
한 번 찾아봅시다
Let's look at the reviews and see what reviews are positive or
긍정적인지 부정적인지 리뷰를 보고
negative and see what the people are saying about the product.
사람들이 상품에 대해 뭐라고 하는지 살펴봅시다
So here's what I'm gonna do.
이렇게 할 겁니다
We're gonna sort
리뷰를
the reviews based on the predicted
예측 감성 순으로
sentiment and explore.
정렬하고 조사합니다
And the cool thing here is the predicted sentiment is a much more fine grain
예측 감성은 긍정, 부정에서
description of whether we've used positive or negative.
훨씬 세밀하다는 게 큰 장점이죠
The stars are really skewed, five stars, four stars, three stars, one star, and
평점은 아주 편향되어 있습니다 5점, 4점, 3점, 1점
this will tell you how far along the spectrum you are.
이래선 범위의 어디쯤인지 가늠이 어렵죠
But now that we have this numbers, this extra column, we can do a lot more.
숫자와 추가 열이 있으니 더 잘 할 수 있습니다
So I'm gonna take this giraffe data, and I'm going to sort it.
먼저 기린 데이터를 정렬합니다
So all I have to do is take it, take the same value, and I'm gonna call
그러기 위해선 같은 값에다
the function sort on it.
정렬 함수를 호출하기만 하면 됩니다
And you have to see, what column you're sorting based on.
정렬은
So we're gonna sort based on this new column
predicted_sentiment란 새로운 열을
that we call predicted_sentiment.
기준으로 합니다
And one little trick here, we're gonna say ascending is equal to false.
요령 하나 있는데 오름차순을 거짓으로 설정합니다
So we're still sorting that ascending order is gonna start in descending order.
그러면 내림차순으로 정렬됩니다
Starting from the most positive reviews down to the most negatives.
가장 긍정적인 리뷰에서 가장 부정적인 리뷰 순입니다
Now that we've sorted it we're gonna just show the first few lines of the table.
정렬했으니 표의 처음 몇 줄만 출력해 봅시다
And what you should see is that the reviews are now sorted
감성을 기준으로
based on that sentiment.
정렬되어 있어야 합니다
So the very top here, we have the most positive one has predicted
맨 위에는 가장 긍정적인 리뷰의
sentiment of 1.9999 and they all sorted.
예측 감성은 0.9999입니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]